Abdulrazak Dirie

Curriculum Vitae

PERSONAL DETAILS

Birth April 18, 1992

Address 6 dabka st waberi, Mogadishu

Phone +252 (0)61 599 1378 Alt.Phone +252 (0)62 599 1378

Mail abdulrazak.dirie@gmail.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I described myself as a highly skilled IT professional and expert on the developing of small and medium Enterprise Applications. I am also a talented and genuine data mining professional who is able to work under pressure and rush hours with no confusion. In addition, I have worked on a number of projects as part of a team as well as individually and I was the active project manager of these Projects and during this period, I have branded myself as a reliable and effective member in the team. As a result, I was hired by a number of private and government-owned institutions to assist them with the management of their IT department and projects as well. In short, I have 5+ years working experience in ICT Management, Project management, Software Development, Database Administration, Data analyst, Artificial Intelligence, Big Data management and Data science.

EDUCATION

MSc. Computer Science and Applied mathematics

2017 - 2018

University of the Witwatersrand, South Africa

In this degree, I focused on project management, data analysis, big data management, Artificial Intelligence and data science.

BSc honours. Computer Science

2016-2017

University of the Witwatersrand, South Africa

In this period, the areas that I worked were machine vision, artificial intelligence, deep learning and object detection and recognition. The course project which I developed was vehicle detection and tracking system using CNN.

BSc Undergraduate. Computer Science and IT

2009-2013

Benadir University, Somalia

During this period, I majored Computer Science and mathematics. The main courses which I focused on include: software development, ICT management, Mathematics, Statistics, Accounting Intro, Project management and database administration.

Diploma. ICT Management

2010-2011

SIIT Institute (Part time), Somalia

I studied Computer hardware installation and repairing, network installation and configuration, and whole ICT management.

High School

2006-2009

Mohamud Harbi Secondary school, Somalia

WORK EXPERIENCE

Founder & CEO, Software Developer

2019-2020

Horn Technology AND Horn AI training Center, East Africa, Full-time

Duputy Manager and ICT manager

2017-2018

Savemore General Trading - South Africa, Full-time

Admin Assistance

2017-2017

Afrah General Trading Ltd, South Africa, Part-time

Undergraduate Tutoring

2016-2016

University of the Witwatersrand, South Africa, Full-time

Logistic Officer and ICT assistance

2014-2015

 $Noble\ Interprises,\ Mozambique,\ Full-time$

ICT Admin
Benadir University, Somalia, Full-time

2013-2014

IT professional

2012-2013

Horseed ICT (Internship), Somalia, Full-time

Mathematics teacher

Uhud primary School, Somalia, Part-time

2009-2011

SOCIAL ACTIVITIES

Head of Students

2017-2018

Somali Students at Wits, South Africa

General Secretary

2015-2016

Somali Association in South Africa (SASA), South Africa.

Head of Electoral committee

2015-2016

Somali Student Association in South Africa (SSA in SA).

Board member

2015-2018

Somali Student Association in South Africa.

Education campaigner, Famous in the field

2015-2018

SKILLS

Languages Somali (mother tongue)

English (fluent), Arabic (good)

Technical Data analysis and explanation, ICT Management,

Big Data management and Data Science,

Computer Programming, Microsoft Office Packages. Database Administration, Project Management, LATEX for writing reports and other documents.

Other Good communication, Interpersonal skills,

Management skills, Logistic Management,

Quick learning, Critical thinking,

Problem Solving, Motivational speaker, Respect for diversity,

Emotional intelligence, Time management, Teamwork.

AWARDS

School Postgraduate merit Award from the University of the Witwatersrand.

Community Education Campaigner award from the Somali Community

CONFERENCES AND WORKSHOPS

Data Science Acceleration Engagement (workshop).

IBM, South Africa

7days, 2018

Big Data Machine Learning, Cloud OnBoar(Training)

Google Inc, South Africa

Full day, 2018

Forum on Internet Freedom in Africa (Conference).

 $Collaboration \ on \ International \ ICT \ Policy \ for \ East \ and$

Southern Africa (CIPESA), South Africa

4days, 2017

REFERENCES

Prof. Turgay Celik, Professor of Computer Science University of the witwatersrand,

South Africa.

Phone: +27 (0) 11 717 6168

Email: turgay.celik@wits.ac.za

Mrs. Mohamed Amin, Director of Savemore LTd.

Phone:

Email: savemore2@hotmail.com